Four strangers become friends. Four friends become
heroes. On the road to Silverado.
Silverado is a western, action film directed by Lawrence Kasdan.
Four unwitting heroes cross paths on their journey
to the sleepy town of Silverado.
Little do they know the town where their family and friends reside has
been taken over by a corrupt sheriff and a murderous posse.
It's up to the sharp-shooting foursome to save the day, but first they have to
break each other out of jail, and learn who their real friends are.
Paden, played by Kevin Kline.
Emmett, played by Scott Glenn.
Malachi 'Mal' Johnson, played by Danny Glover.
Jake, played by Kevin Costner.
Cobb, played by Brian Dennehy.
Hannah, played by Rosanna Arquette.
Silverado is a 1985 American Western film that was produced and directed by
Lawrence Kasdan, and written by Kasdan and his brother Mark.
It stars Kevin Kline, Scott Glenn, Danny Glover, and Kevin Costner.
The supporting cast features Brian Dennehy, Rosanna Arquette, John
Cleese, Jeff Goldblum, Lynne Whitfield, and Linda Hunt.
The film was produced by Columbia Pictures and Delphi III Productions, and distributed to
theatres by Columbia, and by Sony Pictures Home Entertainment for home media.
The original soundtrack, with a score composed by Bruce
Broughton, was released by Geffen Records.
On November 12, 2005, an expanded two-disc version of the
score was released by the Intrada Records label.
Silverado premiered in the United States on July 10, 1985.
Through an 11-week run, the film was shown at 1,190 theaters at its
widest release, and grossed $32,192,570 at the box office.
Generally met with positive critical reviews, it was nominated for Best
Sound and Best Original Score at the 58th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, sheriff, saloon, fight, new mexico.